over Robert to New York as an offensive
coordinator, really to call it himself.
I think he gained a lot of experience
there. And then I'm going to transition
to LA where, you know, Sean McVay there
head coaching breeding factory there.
He's able to, you know, learn under Sean
and I know that helped him as well. So,
he's learned that, you know, three great
spots. I think he was with DQ as well,
maybe. So, he's just learned at a lot of
different spots from a lot of really
great head coaches and I think
I want to see that tree kind of keep
growing like it has.
Uh it's uh it's impressive to see, you
know, how many guys and for me first
starting out as a coach in 2017 to see
how many guys from that staff right as
going on to be head coaches or even to
become coordinators. I was
at home a couple weeks ago and I saw
when I was cleaning out some old boxes
and I saw old picture from 2017 San
Francisco 49ers a team picture and I
just started going through all the head
all of the coaching staff and just to
see from 2017 to see where a lot of
those guys are now in leadership
positions. I think it just speaks to,
you know, Kyle Shanahan and the job that
he does, John Lynch and the staff that
they were able to put together. Speaking
of tight end position, you guys extended
Dalton after career high in catches.
Just want to start with Dalton, but I'd
like to ask you about the other guys
after Dalton.
First off with Dalton, I think the thing
that jumped out with Dalton, he he took
a a huge step this year
uh this past year from
Yeah, it's
I mean, him and CJ just having that
connection is it seemed like whenever CJ
got out of the pocket or needed a guy
down field, Dalton was that guy he was
throwing the ball to, you know, making
some incredible plays for us. So,
definitely love him in the passing game,
but what he also enhanced this past year
was his blocking and I think he did a
really good job of improving, you know,
as a blocker standing out there as best
he can. So, you know, he's very
deserving
of the contract extension and he's a
really great teammate, great locker room
guy, great leader for us as well. So,
I'm excited to keep him. And where would
you like to see Brevin and Cade and
obviously Brevin's got to get healthy.
You guys have praised Brevin when he's
healthy, but for Cade health too and
play, where would you like to see him
area for
>> Sure. For our our younger tight ends who
are, you know, behind Dalton, first and
foremost is getting healthy. Getting
healthy is going to give those guys a
chance to actually get on the field, do
football and actually get better at
football. So, first step foremost, get
healthy and then just attack every day
with the mindset that you're going to
get better. So, hopefully we see those
improvements, you know, from Brevin and
Cade. 49ers getting in the Christian
Kirk.
So, what are the 49ers getting in
Christian Kirk? What are we
Christian Kirk is a man, outstanding
human, great great young man. I really
uh provided a lot to our locker room
from a leadership standpoint of helping
out. We had a lot of young receivers
this past year. I thought Christian did
a really good job of helping out those
young guys. They're able to lean on him
to gain some of his insight and the
experience that he's had from from being
a pro for a while.
Uh but he can still make a lot of plays
for you. A guy who can really stretch
the field and make big plays. Also can
do it from the slot perspective of
running some of the choice routes and
winning in man coverage. So, you're
getting a really talented veteran guy
who's a really good locker room leader
as well.
Is it a lot of plan for you guys to
extend the fifth year options on Stroud
and Anderson? I don't know if that's the
plan.
How does his leadership help your
secondary?
You know, Reed helps us helps us from a
standpoint of just the the instincts
that which he plays with. I think he's
really good at things and also from the
communication standpoint. That's the
thing that jumped out to me. Like just
watching the film, you see if
something's going wrong, everybody's
looking back at Reed like, "Hey, what's
the communication? What should we be in
here?" So, I'm excited to get a guy
who's a communicator, who's a leader,
who's an instinctive playmaker and a
really good teammate from what I hear.
With you guys having time away from the
season the way it ended, what kind of
conversations you have with CJ and and
what are you expecting from him as you I
know it didn't end the way he wanted,
but you expressed a lot of support from
him coming away from that. And then what
do you expect now from him as he comes
back? You know, what I what I've seen
from CJ
uh the support has hasn't wavered from
me to CJ. I let him know that again,
just reaffirm that support for him. And
also I see a guy who's dialed in to the
off season and really working.
In the past couple off seasons, he
hasn't had that full time to really,
whether it was injury or other things.
Like so, he hasn't had that full time to
dedicate himself in off season. So, I
see a guy he's in in full grind mode
right now. So, I'm excited to see, you
know, what comes, you know, from the
work that he's putting in. It's only
going to be better. The mindset is
right, physically he's in a really good
space, mentally in a really good space.
So, I'm I'm excited to see him get back
to work and get better. And you guys did
a lot of work on his line in front of as
he expressed any, you know, excitement
about the you know, that that bolstered
protection and everything you guys
investment you made basically also in
him through that. Yeah, the investment
we made in offensive line really
enhanced our team, all right? And CJ
should be the beneficiary of that as
well. Uh he's excited about the moves we
made. What I What I love about CJ is,
you know, the guys we are signing in
this time of free agency,
he's the first guy like, "Can I get a
guy's number? Can I reach out?" He wants
to reach out to those guys and really
welcome them, you know, to the Texans
family and it means so much to him and
it means so much to us. And I know from
a free agent perspective or new guy
going into a new situation, when you
hear from the starting quarterback from
that team, it it carries a lot of
weight. So, I'm really thankful for him
and his mindset of having, you know,
that on his mind while he's working. I
want to make sure I welcome all of our
new teammates in the right way. What do
you like about
Nick Caserio
and and how do you hope he can grow
as he goes into his second season? What
I like about Nick from his first year,
first time calling plays, I like how
he was able to morph and transition
into, you know, kind of what we needed
to work for us to win games. So, just
and that's what I I knew about him going
in, his flexibility of being able to go
in any manner we needed to go to help us
win games, he was able to do that.
We did a a better job from a protection
standpoint than in years
previous years when it came to, you
know, not getting the quarterback hit as
much. I thought we did a better job
there. Still looking to enhance and
improve there, but I thought Nick did a
really good job of of setting the
protections where our protection schemes
were sound and our our players up front,
they did a for the most part did a
really good job of being sound in where
they were going and how they were
picking things up.
Along the lines with the offensive
lineman, you got asked about linebackers
a little bit and you said sometimes you
you kind of know when a pro or a guy
that could be a pro. How do you approach
looking at college linebackers and kind
of the way the game works in college
versus how you might use them in pro in
the pros? Yeah, the college linebacker
has definitely changed a lot. You're
seeing a lot more uh hybrid players when
it comes to the linebacker position,
guys doing multiple things. All right,
guys are playing from that stack
linebacker position, but also they're
moving down to the edge, also rushing
from an outside linebacker perspective.
So, guys are doing a lot of different
things. So, I think one, you're seeing a
lot more athletic linebackers
who can play well in space. Being in
space isn't unfamiliar to them and I
think that's the one thing that sets
guys apart on the NFL level. All right,
from college to NFL, can you transition?
Can you as a linebacker, can you be out
in space one-on-one with a guy like
Jahmyr Gibbs and go make that play or
are you shaking in your cleats? So, it's
guys who can do that, they're confident
making those tackles in space, they'll
they'll excel at this level. Uh there's
not many guys that can do that because
it's it's a tough task. You're going
against such great talented guys on our
on our level.
Coach Demeco, I was at the media party
last night. I had a chance to talk to
some of the brass from your organization
and some of those people were mentioning
how glad they are that you're such a
solid family person and how they feel
like that is such a core
cog in the organization. So, to that
end, I'm curious beyond the football
side, how much when you're having
conversations with some of the players
on your team, do you kind of vessel into
you know, just not only the status of
their lives, but what else that they can
be doing to
strengthen the foundation within their
own home so that they're bringing that
energy into the organization as well?
Thank you for the question. That's
one thing that's near and dear to me and
it's one of the reasons I said why I got
into why I got into coaching.
I really
I got into coaching to help players, all
right? And it's not just on the field,
but off the field as well. So,
that's what still drives me today. So,
when a young man comes in my office and
we're talking non-football stuff, I
always tell them like, "This is why I
coach. Like this was the reason why."
Because being able to have those real
conversations, all right? As as
as men, like I know guys want to aspire
to be family men, husbands, fathers. And
for me having that experience, being
able to
give them uh some tips
ideas on things that work, things that
haven't worked. I don't have it all
together and I let guys know that. Are
you going to make mistakes along the
way, but it's it's the same as you are
on the field, you want to continue to
grow as a player, it's the same off the
field as a father, as a husband. You're
going to mess some things up, understand
that. But also understand that you learn
from those things and you continue to
grow and and be there, you know, for
your family no matter what. And so,
I love having those conversations. Many
of those conversations I can I love
having those over over football
sometimes. So, I'm
I'm thankful to have
such a great locker room of a lot of
great guys. And that's the thing that
sticks out to me when we're looking at
guys in the draft, looking at free
agents,
what type of man are they
in the locker room? What type of man are
they outside of the field? That really
drives me more than the football. And
so, I
I respect that we have a locker room of
men that is indicative of that. I love
guys like Will Anderson, C.J. Stroud,
and then Ceasear Shaheer. He's just We
have a ton of great
great young men on our team who I'm I'm
proud to be their coach, not just
because of the football, but because of
who they are as men. To me, I didn't
even look at the
other two part of it.
>> [laughter]
>> What
We didn't ask you about Bridgeland and
how you think it'll help you guys in
football. I know it's down the road. And
also, I just wanted to ask about Jaylen
Smith at the end.
With the with the new facility at
Bridgeland that the Texans are
developing, I think it's
it's such a
it's such an awesome move by the Texans.
I'm thankful for
the McNair family for what they're
doing. They're going to move the
organization forward, making a such a
big decision. It's needed. From us, we
are one of I think three or four teams
who are still operating out of the
stadium. We of course have our
challenges of working at the stadium.
So, I love that this new facility is
really football forward. All decisions
are being made to make it more efficient
for players, the access, how the
building will be set up. It's just going
to be much more efficient for our
players and for coaches as well. And
also for the community there in
Bridgeland, I think it's going to be
very impactful for everyone around. And
Jaylen, do you expect him after his
meniscus thing to be ready? And what do
you think of his opportunity year two to
get be that kind of third corner? Jaylen
is is working extremely hard.
He's there every day grinding. And he's
I'm excited to get him back, see what
how he looks in training camp.
Thanks, coach. All right. Thanks for
your time. No problem. Appreciate you
guys coming out.